# ABIGAIL DEPRIEST

Software Developer

### CONTACT

- 859.321.1464
- abby.depriest@gmail.com
- Q Nashville, TN
- github.com/abigail-depriest
- www.linkedin.com/in/abigaildepriest

# **PROJECTS**

FEATHERED FRIENDS (Front-End)
Created for bird enthusiasts who
take a casual approach to birding.
React-based full CRUD app using
Firebase storage and Google
Authentication.

<u>View Code</u> <u>View Netlify</u>

React | JavaScript | Node.JS | CSS Firebase | Postman | Next.JS

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- lavaScript
- Next.|s
- React
- Node.JS
- Python
- CSS
- Django
- HTMI
- SOL
- Postman
- Firebase
- Bootstrap
- Git/Github

#### **PROFILE**

I have a diverse professional background in customer service, hospitality, and the arts, and I am transitioning into a career in software development. My experience has equipped me with strong problem-solving, adaptability, and communication skills with an over-arching emphasis on collaboration. I look forward to applying my strengths to a career in tech.

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - APPRENTICE

October 2023 - September 2024

Intensive part-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. The final half of the program are executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in JavaScript, as well as in the React framework
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Solution Design: white-boarding and wireframes
- Leveraged Django for creating and editing servergenerated web applications
- Created RESTful API's with Django REST framework
- Retrieved and stored database information with SQLite
- Practiced testing with Python's unit test framework

# ABIGAIL DEPRIEST

Software Developer

#### CONTACT

- 859.321.1464
- abby.depriest@gmail.com
- Nashville, TN
- github.com/abigail-depriest
- www.linkedin.com/in/abigaildepriest

### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School Certificate, Web Development

October 2023 - September 2024

#### University of Kentucky

B.A. in Music

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Frist Art Museum

ART HANDLER

2019 - Present

- Process incoming and outgoing art for exhibitions
- Operating equipment for installations and deinstallations
- Taking detailed instructions from curators and exhibitions designers
- Work with artists to ensure sculptures and three-dimensional objects are accurately installed and displayed

#### **Deacon's New South**

SERVER

2021 - Present

- Serve guests in a responsive, prompt and courteous manner
- Educate guests on menu items and assist with food and wine pairings
- Communicate guest needs effectively and efficiently to both back of house and front of house staff

#### **Union Common**

SERVER

2015-2020

- Ensure that steps of service are being completed
- Maintain a professional yet hospitable environment
- Careful listening and communication with guests
- Working both independently and as a part of the service team to achieve a larger goal for the restaurant

#### **City Winery**

WINE CAPTAIN, SOMMELIER 2014-2016

- Wine inventory and organization
- Primary resource for guests and employees navigating the extensive wine menu
- Acted as a liaison between event planners and servers to effectively execute private events